Guide to the Leo Bogart Papers, 1912-2010 and undated RL.10146
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Series, 1914-2005 and undated, 84 boxes
  - Late Career Subseries, 1988-2005 and undated
    - Gannett Center/Freedom Forum
      - Seminars and presentations
        - TV and cable speech notes, circa 1994 (Box 17)
      - Oakland Tribune consulting, 1992-1993 (Box 17)
    - General correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
    - Innovation International Media Consulting Group
      - Consulting Projects
        - American Association for Retired Persons (AARP), 2003 and undated (Box 17)
        - Libération newspaper; Paris, France, 1999 (Box 17)
        - Reexamining the Web Business Model study, 2002 (Box 17)
        - Russian print media, 2004 (Box 17)
        - Spain, Portugal, and Latin America
          - Caracas, Venezuela, El Universal management seminar, 1998 (Box 17)
          - Dominican Republic, El Caribe, 2000-2001 (Box 17)
          - El Salvador, 1996 (Box 17)
          - Latin American press project
            - Correspondence, writings, and clippings, 1992-1997 and undated, 1 of 2 folders (Box 17)
            - Correspondence, writings, and clippings (continued), 1992-1997 and undated, 2 of 2 folders (Box 18)
            - Newspaper case histories: Latin America, 1996
              - Itinerary (Box 18)
              - Argentina (Buenos Aires); Clarin (Box 18)
              - Bolivia (La Paz); La Razon and El Presencia (Box 18)
              - Colombia (Bogotá); El Espectador and El Tiempo (Box 18)
              - Colombia (Cali); El Pais (Box 18)
              - Costa Rica (San José); La Nacion (Box 18)
              - Ecuador (Quito); El Comercio and Hoy (Box 18)
              - El Salvador (San Salvador); El Diario de Hoy (Box 18)
              - Guatemala (Guatemala City); Siglo XXI (Box 18)
              - Honduras (San Pedro Sula); La Prensa (Box 18)
              - Mexico (Mexico City); El Universal and Reforma (Box 18)
              - Nicaragua (Managua); La Prensa (Box 18)
              - Panama (Panama City); La Prensa (Box 18)
              - Peru (Lima); El Comercio (Box 19)
              - Venezuela (Caracas); El Nacional (Box 19)
          - Panama, El Universal, 1999 (Box 19)
          - Lisbon, Portugal audience rankings, 1998 (Box 19)
          - Madrid, Spain; ABC newspaper redesign, 2004, 2 folders (Box 19)
          - Madrid, Spain; El Sol, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
          - Miscellaneous South American newspaper summaries, circa 1996-1997 (Box 19)
        - Ukraine newspaper launch project, 2004-2005, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - World Association of Newspapers weekend edition survey, 2000 (Box 19)
      - Meeting materials, 1996-2001
        - Chile trip, 2000 (Box 19)
      - Printed materials
        - Capturing and Captivating Young Readers: 50 Editorial Strategies, 2005 (Box 19)
        - Innovations in Newspapers World Report annual publication, 1999-2002, 3 folders (Box 19)
        - Innovations in Newspapers World Report annual publication, 2003-2005, 3 folders (Box 20)
        - Publicitas Promotion Network, circa 2004 (Box 20)
      - Survey methodology remarks, Brazil, 2000 (Box 20)
    - International newspaper web site survey data, 2000, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Legal consulting
      - Michael Jackson molestation trial materials, Chandler v. Jackson, 1993-1999, 1-5 of 7 folders (Box 20)
      - Michael Jackson molestation trial materials, Chandler v. Jackson (continued), 1993-1999, 6-7 of 7 folders (Box 21)
      - Technical Advisory Service for Attorneys (TASA) materials, 2002 (Box 21)
      - Trichloroethylene (TCE) groundwater contamination lawsuit correspondence, Valenzuela v. Hughes Aircraft Company; Tuscon, Arizona, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Leveraging Newspaper Assets media usage study, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Obor Foundation
      - Arab translation and publishing program, 1994-1995 (Box 21)
      - Conference on Books in Morocco 1995 (Box 21)
      - Printed materials, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Online classifieds study, 2001 (Box 21)
    - Russian news media project, 1993-1997 (Box 21)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA) Morocco public opinion research visit, 1998 (Box 21)
  - Newspaper Advertising Bureau (NAB) Subseries, 1914-1990 and undated
    Documents Bogart's twenty-nine year executive career with the Newspaper Advertising Bureau (NAB), the advertising and promotion organization for the newspaper industry. Bogart began work with the NAB as Vice President of Marketing Planning and Research in 1960 and was promoted to Executive Vice President and General Manager in 1966. During his tenure with the NAB, Bogart was the architect of most of the major research studies. Bogart led two major research projects, the Newspaper Readership Project from 1977-1983 and the Future of Advertising Project from 1979-1988. The goal of the Newspaper Readership Project was to make recommendations to reverse declines in newspaper readership that begun in the 1920s and were threatening the vitality of the newspaper industry during the 1970s and 1980s. The Future of Advertising Project was formed shortly afterward to address newspapers' decline in national advertising revenues that began in the 1960s due largely to the rise of television. Recommendations from the Future of Advertising Project led to standardization in advertising formats and invoices across newspapers. This subseries is divided into three sections: General, Newspaper Readership Project, and Future of Advertising Project. General consists mainly of materials related to various research projects at the NAB. For slides of NAB presentations, see the Photographs & Slides Series. Speeches and presentations in this subseries report directly on the workings of the NAB; for all other speeches, see the Writings and Speeches Subseries. Arranged alphabetically within category except for speeches and meetings, which are arranged chronologically.
    - General (Box 22)
      - Correspondence
        - Advertising expenditures, 1977-1986 (Box 22)
        - Association for Education in Journalism, 1972-1985 (Box 22)
        - Australia/New Zealand, 1980-1981 (Box 22)
        - Board of Directors, 1980-1988 (Box 22)
        - Circulation and readership
          - Distribution, 1972-1988 (Box 22)
          - Favor, Cy, 1970-1987 (Box 22)
          - General circulation correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 22)
          - Survey of apartment dwellers, 1973 (Box 22)
          - Williams, Fred, 1973-1974 (Box 22)
        - Creative Newspaper Awards
          - Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 22)
          - Award winners, 1989-1990 (Box 22)
        - Dues, 1986 (Box 22)
        - The Future of Downtown conference proposal, 1967 (Box 22)
        - General, 1965-1989, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - Interoffice, 1974-1988 (Box 22)
        - Media Records crisis, 1970-1977, 2 folders (Box 22)
        - New technology, 1976-1988 (Box 22)
        - Print versus broadcast advertising, 1963-1985 (Box 22)
        - South Africa, 1976-1979 (Box 22)
        - Supplier correspondence
          - Belden, 1977-1983 (Box 22)
          - Compmark III, 1977-1981 (Box 22)
          - Market Opinion Research, 1976-1986 (Box 23)
        - Television, 1964-1987, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Meetings and Conferences
        - 1968 Jan. 17, INAE convention (Box 23)
        - 1972-1979, The Future of Retailing meetings (Box 23)
        - 1973 Mar. 8, ABC meeting (Box 23)
        - 1973 Apr. 24, ANPA annual meeting speech (Box 23)
        - 1973 Aug. 8, Retaining the Newspaper Audience meeting (Box 23)
        - 1973 Sept. 13, Selective Perception and Communication: A Fresh Look at Recurrent Questions seminar (Box 23)
        - 1973 Nov. 14, A.A.A.A. Eastern Region convention (Box 23)
        - 1974-1988, The Future of the Grocery Business meetings (Box 23)
        - 1975 Dec. 4-5, Boston Globe readership and circulation meeting (Box 23)
        - 1975-1988, Board of Directors meetings and presentations, 2 folders (Box 23)
        - 1976 Mar. 19, Detroit Adcraft Club meeting, The Selective Customer (Box 23)
        - 1976 June 5-10, ANPA Research Institute production conference (Box 23)
        - 1976 Aug. 11-12, News Research Committee Summit meeting (Box 23)
        - 1977 Jan 10, NRMA Board of Directors meeting (Box 23)
        - 1977 July 28-29, IAPA Bogotá, Colombia (Box 23)
        - 1977 Oct. 25-28, APME convention (Box 23)
        - 1978 Oct. 12-13, Holman Newsprint Symposium, Sweden (Box 23)
        - 1979 Feb. 20-21, Louisville, Kentucky Courier-Journal meeting (Box 23)
        - 1979 June 17-21, ICMA sales conference (Box 23)
        - 1979 June 26, Markets of the Eighties (Box 23)
        - 1979 Sept. 20, Florida Newspaper Advertising Executives meeting (Box 23)
        - 1980 Jan. 20-23, INAE sales conference (Box 23)
        - 1980 Feb. 11-12, Freedom Newspapers meeting (Box 24)
        - 1980 June 30, ICMA meeting (Box 24)
        - 1980 July 2, Sonoma Publishing Company meeting, Finland (Box 24)
        - 1980 Sept. 24, Newspaper Advertising in the New Era of Telecommunications conference, 2 folders (Box 24)
        - 1980 Nov. 4-6, ABC conference (Box 24)
        - 1981 Jan. 11, Satellite network committee meeting (Box 24)
        - 1981 Nov. 29, Alpha Beta meeting (Box 24)
        - 1982 Jan. 31-Feb. 3, INAME sales conference (Box 24)
        - 1982 May 25, Newspapers: Today and Tomorrow panel discussion (Box 24)
        - 1982 Sept. 14, NAB and Food Marketing Institute board meeting (Box 24)
        - 1982-1989, ANPA and NAB joint meetings (Box 24)
        - 1982-1988 ANPA Readership and Marketing Committee meetings (Box 24)
        - 1983 Apr. 26, Press conference (Box 24)
        - 1983 Sept. 15, Des Moines Register meeting (Box 24)
        - 1983 Dec., Bogotá, Colombia conference (Box 24)
        - 1983-1984, ANPA, NAB, & ABC liaison committee meetings (Box 24)
        - 1984 Jan. 29-Feb. 1, INAME conference (Box 24)
        - 1984 May 17, Newspaper Day (Box 24)
        - 1984 June 5, Newsprint Information Committee meeting (Box 24)
        - 1984 Oct., Cox Newspapers editors and publishers meeting (Box 24)
        - 1985 Apr. 14-17, Newspaper Research Council conference (Box 24)
        - 1986 Sept. 9, Media Research luncheon (Box 24)
        - 1986 Dec. 9-10, Television presentation meetings (Box 24)
        - 1989 July 31, Advertising in the 1990s conference (Box 24)
      - Publications
        - Advertising Dimension Standards for Daily Newspapers, 1975 (Box 24)
        - Annual Report, 1989 (Box 24)
        - Catalog of Materials and Services, 1990-1991, 1991 (Box 24)
        - Key Facts 1989: Newspapers, Advertising & Marketing, 1989 (Box 24)
        - Newspaper Advertising Bureau: What It Is, What It Does, 1984 (Box 24)
        - Promotional brochures, 1988-1991 and undated (Box 24)
        - Psychographics: A Study of Personality, Life-style, and Consumption Patterns, 1983 (Box 24)
        - Research Note articles, 1981-1983 (Box 24)
        - 75 Years of the Newspaper Advertising Bureau, 1988 (Box 24)
        - Today's Teenagers: Tomorrow's Readers, 1989 (Box 24)
        - The Turbulent Depths of Marketing: An Analysis of Supermarket Scanner Data, 1984 (Box 24)
        - A Way to Win: Strategies to Evaluate and Improve Your Readership and Circulation, 1990 (Box 24)
      - Research (Box 25)
        - Advertising Performance Project
          - Correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 25)
          - Reports, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 25)
        - Advertising messages research, 1983-1988 (Box 25)
        - Audience research data bank materials, 1972-1979 (Box 25)
        - Brain wave research
          - Clippings, 1976-1977 and undated (Box 25)
          - Correspondence, 1970-1987, 2 folders (Box 25)
          - Eye tracking equipment brochures, 1984 and undated (Box 25)
          - Notes, undated (Box 25)
        - Children and young adults
          - The Mini Page packet, 1978 (Box 25)
          - Minneapolis Star Smile Factory packet, 1978 (Box 25)
          - Television and children, 1972-1982 (Box 25)
          - Teenage audience study, 1987-1989 (Box 25)
          - Youth study, 1970 and undated (Box 25)
        - Clippings and notes, 1965-1983, 3 folders (Box 25)
        - CompuServe experiment correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 25)
        - Credibility of newspapers, 1983-1984 (Box 25)
        - Direct mail advertising, 1980-1984 and undated (Box 25)
        - Editorial inventory study, 1967-1975 (Box 26)
        - Eye camera study, 1961-1978 (Box 26)
        - Football viewing study, 1969 (Box 26)
        - The Future of the Grocery Business study
          - Agricultural economists survey, 1974-1988 (Box 26)
          - Project materials, 1974-1984 and undated (Box 26)
          - Questionnaires, 1974-1987, 2 folders (Box 26)
        - The Future of Retailing study
          - Clippings, 1960-1973 and undated (Box 26)
          - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 26)
          - Questionnaires, 1972 (Box 26)
          - Summary, 1972 (Box 26)
        - How Did It Happen? booklet correspondence, 1970 (Box 26)
        - How to Estimate the Size of the Local Advertising Market and Your Share of It report, 1989 (Box 26)
        - ICMA circulation managers survey, 1976 (Box 26)
        - Ideas and proposals, 1960-1985 (Box 26)
        - Inserts/special sections materials, 1982-1989 (Box 26)
        - Leisure time survey, 1984 (Box 26)
        - The Measure of a Medium study, 1983 (Box 26)
        - Media trends materials, 1985-1986 (Box 26)
        - Membership surveys, 1973-1985 (Box 26)
        - Merrill Lynch campaign, 1987 (Box 26)
        - A Million Miles of Newspapers study, 1972-1974 (Box 26)
        - Minneapolis Star-Tribune circulation study, 1973 (Box 26)
        - Movie study, 1985-1986 (Box 26)
        - NABSCAN project, 1980-1987 and undated (Box 26)
        - National advertiser use of daily newspapers study, 1984-1987 (Box 26)
        - News About the News Media study, 1971 (Box 26)
        - Newspaper audience research, 1969-1979 (Box 27)
        - Newspaper Preprint Corporation project
          - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 27)
          - NAB Preprint Division, 1969-1975 (Box 27)
          - Report Relating to Newspaper Preprint Corporation 1975 (Box 27)
        - Newspaper pricing strategies study proposals, 1986 (Box 27)
        - Newspaper Procedures, Attitudes, and Uses for Advertising Linage Measurement report, 1973-1974 (Box 27)
        - Newsplan program, 1979-1980 (Box 27)
        - The 1990 Daily and Sunday Newspaper Audience study, 1991 (Box 27)
        - One Bill, One Order materials, undated (Box 27)
        - Project IV - How, When and Where materials, 1967 and undated (Box 27)
        - Project V - When People Want to Know materials, 1967 and undated (Box 27)
        - Project VI - What Can One Newspaper Ad Do?
          - Clippings, 1967-1969 and undated (Box 27)
          - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 27)
          - Reports, 1967-1968 and undated (Box 27)
        - Project VII - Shoppers on the Move
          - Clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 27)
          - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 27)
          - Reports, 1974 (Box 27)
        - Project IX - Newspapers: The Retail Action Medium proposal, 1976 (Box 27)
        - Psychographics research study, 1971-1973 (Box 27)
        - Roper research for Television Information Office analysis, 1962-1979 (Box 27)
        - Small space study, 1972 (Box 27)
        - Standard ad units recommendation, 1980-1984 (Box 27)
        - Standardized newspaper audience proposal, 1970 (Box 27)
        - Television research
          - Audience research, 1969 (Box 27)
          - Cable television, 1977-1985 (Box 27)
          - Clippings and notes, 1973-1975 (Box 27)
          - Golden West Broadcasters study on television commercial impact, 1973-1978 (Box 27)
          - A Study of the Consistency of Local Market Television Ratings summary, 1968-1972 (Box 27)
          - Television commercial recall studies, 1974-1990 (Box 28)
        - A Test of Same-Day Promotion of Coupon Value, 1984-1986 (Box 28)
        - Undaily newspaper study, 1976-1978 (Box 28)
        - The Working Woman study, 1972-1976 (Box 28)
        - Young homemakers study, 1973-1974 (Box 28)
      - Speeches
        - 1964 Nov. 4, Media Research Directors speech (Box 28)
        - 1965, International Federation of Newspaper Publishers speech (Box 28)
        - 1967 Apr. 27, A $2.8 Billion Misunderstanding, NAB annual meeting (Box 28)
        - 1968, Some Characteristics of Our Newspaper Readers, ICMA (Box 28)
        - 1970 Jan. 21, INAE research workshop speech (Box 28)
        - 1970 Apr. 21, The Changing Competitive Picture in National Advertising, NAB annual meeting (Box 28)
        - 1970 Oct. 21, ABC speech notes (Box 28)
        - 1971 Apr. 20, ANPA annual meeting speech (Box 28)
        - 1973 Apr. 24, ANPA annual meeting speech (Box 28)
        - 1974 Sept., The Future of the Food Business (Box 28)
        - 1976 Jan. 13, The Selective Customer, NRMA (Box 28)
        - 1976 Oct. 20, ABC meeting presentation (Box 28)
        - 1976 Dec. 8, Marketing the High Utility Medium, National Conference for Newspaper Associations (Box 28)
        - 1977 Apr. 18, Building Newspaper Circulation, Inter-State Circulation Managers' Association (Box 28)
        - 1977, INAE speeches (Box 28)
        - 1979 Jan. 31, INAE report (Box 28)
        - 1979, ASNE presentation (Box 28)
        - 1980, INAE report (Box 28)
        - 1981 Jan. 8, INAE convention report (Box 28)
        - 1982 Apr. 27, ANPA conference speech (Box 28)
        - 1982 July 17, INAME Plans Committee meeting report (Box 28)
        - 1982 Oct., Board of Directors meeting speeches (Box 28)
        - 1983 Jan. 25, INAME conference report (Box 28)
        - 1983 June 21, ICMA meeting report (Box 28)
        - 1983 July 18, INAME conference report (Box 28)
        - 1984 June 27, Transactions and Experiences: There is a Difference, ICMA (Box 28)
        - 1985 Apr.11, ASNE meeting presentation (Box 28)
        - 1985 May 5, Board of Directors meeting report (Box 28)
        - 1985 May 8, ANPA convention report (Box 28)
        - 1986 Jan. 28, INAME conference report (Box 28)
        - 1987 May 5, ANPA convention report (Box 28)
        - 1987 July 13, Strategic Selling, INAME (Box 28)
        - 1988 Aug. 30, Coca Cola/Ferguson Rood dinner speech (Box 28)
        - Undated, Sears presentation outline (Box 28)
        - Undated, The 30-Minute Egg presentation (Box 28)
        - Undated, What is the Bureau of Advertising? (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Bureau of Advertising membership contracts, 1914-1917 (Box 28)
        - Leo Bogart is a Heavy Viewer poster, undated (Box 28)
        - Notes, undated (Box 28)
        - Publishers, 1968 and undated (Box 28)
    - Major projects (Box 29)
      - Newspaper Readership Project (NRP), 1965-1984
        - Administrative
          - ANPA publications, 1976-1979 (Box 29)
          - ASNE correspondence, 1978-1984, 3 folders (Box 29)
          - Budget materials, 1980-1983 (Box 29)
          - Correspondence
            - Contributors, 1976-1980 (Box 29)
            - General, 1976-1983, 2 folders (Box 29)
            - Magazine audience mailing, 1977-1978 (Box 29)
            - Silha, Otto, 1976-1982 (Box 29)
          - Information package, 1976 (Box 29)
          - Project planning, 1979 (Box 29)
          - Publicity, 1976-1983 (Box 29)
        - Committee files
          - General files, 1977-1983
            - Committee correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 29)
            - Executive committee wind-down correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 29)
            - Newspaper Readership Council meeting minutes, 1977-1983 (Box 29)
            - Newspaper Readership Council meeting minutes, 1977-1983 (Box 30)
            - Steering committee meeting minutes, 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 30)
          - Equipment & Systems Development committee, 1977-1982
            - Clippings, 1977-1982 (Box 30)
            - Correspondence, 1977-1981, 2 folders (Box 30)
            - Meeting minutes, 1977-1980, 2 folders (Box 30)
            - Notes, undated (Box 30)
            - Radio Shack materials, 1979-1980 (Box 30)
            - Single-copy sales materials, undated (Box 30)
            - Writings, 1979-1980 (Box 30)
          - Promotion & Public Relations committee, 1965-1982
            - Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 30)
            - Crown Zellerbach film correspondence, 1980 (Box 30)
            - Ed Asner commercials correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 30)
            - First Edition film correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 30)
            - First Freedom film correspondence, 1982 (Box 30)
            - I Saw it in the Paper film
              - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 30)
              - Promotional booklet, circa 1979 (Box 30)
            - It's Your Newspaper presentation correspondence, 1981 (Box 30)
            - The Indispensable Newspaper film proposal, 1977 (Box 30)
            - INPA/Jim Pauloski correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 31)
            - International Instructional Television Cooperative, Inc. correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 31)
            - Meeting minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 31)
            - National Better Newspaper Contest, 1981 (Box 31)
            - Newspaper advertising photographs, undated (Box 31)
            - Newspaper in Education program
              - Program materials, 1976-1980 (Box 31)
              - Children's special sections, 1979 (Box 31)
            - Printed materials, 1977-1979 and undated (Box 31)
            - Read All About It presentation correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 31)
            - Southern Newspaper Publishers Association advertisements, 1965-1966 (Box 31)
          - Research committee, 1976-1984
            - ASNE focus group interim report, 1978-1979 (Box 31)
            - ASNE focus group reports, 1979-1984 (Box 31)
            - Carolyn Kent study and response, 1979 (Box 31)
            - Children, Mothers & Newspapers study, 1978 (Box 31)
            - Clippings, 1978-1981 (Box 31)
            - Correspondence, 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 31)
            - Editorial content questionnaire, 1978 (Box 31)
            - Family Weekly studies, 1979 (Box 31)
            - Hispanic readers, 1980 (Box 31)
            - How the Public Gets Its News study, 1977-1978 (Box 32)
            - Marder computer game, 1978 (Box 32)
            - Meeting minutes, 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 32)
            - Newsroom study, 1980 (Box 32)
            - Research program correspondence, 1977 (Box 32)
            - Research, 1976-1979 (Box 32)
            - Research proposals, 1976-1979 (Box 32)
          - Training committee, 1977-1982
            - Articles, 1977-1979 (Box 32)
            - Correspondence, 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 32)
            - Meeting minutes, 1977-1982 (Box 32)
            - Newspaper carrier survey, undated (Box 32)
            - Notes, undated (Box 32)
            - Proposals, 1977 (Box 32)
            - Publication correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 32)
        - Meetings and conferences (Box 33)
          - 1978 June 3-8, ANPA production conference (Box 33)
          - 1978 July 16-19, INAE sales conference (Box 33)
          - 1979 Feb. 18-20, Inland Daily Press Association meeting (Box 33)
          - 1980 Sept. 10-12, INPA conference (Box 33)
          - 1981 May 5, ANPA meeting (Box 33)
        - Programs and research
          - Action Line Reporters Association correspondence, 1978 (Box 33)
          - American Academy of Advertising survey, 1978 (Box 33)
          - Background materials, 1969-1976 (Box 33)
          - Black readership
            - Background materials, 1968-1981 (Box 33)
            - Issues workshop on black readership, 1981-1983 (Box 33)
            - Minority recruitment correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 33)